Guide to the American Service Institute Records, ca. 1920-1961 AIS.1963.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Special Projects and Daily Activities, I.
  - Transfer-Community Committees, 17.
    - Advisory Committee, Civic Unity Council, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Advisory Committee, Civic Unity Council, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Advisory Committee, Civic Unity Council, 1947-1951 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Transfer File, 18.
    - Consultation, Resource, Requests. Misc, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Conferences re Group Work Services to foreign born, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Consultation, misc., 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Volunteer Bureau for New Arrivals, 19.
    - Volunteer Bureau for New Arrivals (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence with Volunteer Visitors (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Education and Promotion, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Recruiting Committee, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Reports (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Women's Advisory Committee, minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Women's Advisory Committee, correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Local Organizations and Activities, 20.
    - Action Housing (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Adult Education Council of Greater Pittsburgh, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County Committee for Fair Housing. Practices, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Allegheny General Hospital. Consultant Service, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - American Red Cross, Pittsburgh Chapter (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Boy Scouts of Allegheny County (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Council of Churches (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Department of Public Assistance. Local Organization (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Family and Children Service (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Foreign Policy Association. Pittsburgh (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Catholic Social Service (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Chamber of Commerce (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Foundations... (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Girl Scouts of Allegheny County (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Community Relations Council Local (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Jewish Family and Children's Services (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Juvenile Court of Allegheny County, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lutheran Service Society. Local (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - National Conference of Christians and News. Local (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - National Council of Jewish Women. Pittsburgh Section (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Neighborhood Centers Association (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Parent-Teachers Associations. Local (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Pennsylvania Citizens Association (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Pittsburgh Association for Improvement of the Poor (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Pittsburgh Child Guidance Center (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Travelers Aid Society-Pittsburgh, Pa (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - United Jewish Federation. Local (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - YMCA - General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Urban League's Committee on Occupancy Patterns in Public Housing., minutes (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Urban League's Committee on Occupancy Patterns in Public Housing, correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Urban League of Pittsburgh (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Commission on Human Relations, 21.
    - Aaronsburg Assembly. Commission Human Relations, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - F.E.P.C. - City of Pittsburgh, August, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - New Commission on Human Relations, (formerly F.E.P.C. C.U.C), 1955 (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
    - Commission on Human Relations and ASI Research, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Advisory Committee/Community Relations Division. Commission on Human Relations, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Integrated Housing Committee of Commission on Human Relations, (Housing for Minorities), 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
    - Research Advisory Committee. Commission of Human Relations, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - YWCA, 22.
    - Young Women's Christian Association. (general) (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - YWCA of Pittsburgh. Consultant Service, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Committee on Inclusiveness - YWCA, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Settlements, 23.
    - Brashear Settlement. Consultant Service, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Irene Kaufmann Settlement. Consultant Service (Box 7, Folder 46-47)
    - Kingsley House, January 17, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Soho Community House. Settlement File (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Woods Run Settlement (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Out of Town Organizations, 24.
    - Adult Education Association, Sec. for non-English speaking adults, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - American Federation of international Institutes (Box 8, Folder 2-5)
    - AFII Merger Proposals, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - AFII - National Newsletter, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - AFII. Training Seminar, January 1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - International Institutes (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - American Friends Service Committee (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - American Immigration Conference, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The American Jewish Committee (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - American Museum of Immigration (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Anti-Defamation League (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Bureau for Intercultural Education (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - C.A.R.E. (Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - The Center for Human Relations Studies (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Citizen's Bureau, The. Marshall Building, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Civic Unity Councils (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Education for American Citizenship. University of Chicago, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Common Council for American Unity (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Council Against Discrimination (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Encampment for Citizenship (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - International Social Service (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - NAIRO, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 26-28)
    - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials (Box 8, Folder 29-30)
    - National Council on Naturalization and Citizenship. New York City (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - National Federation of Settlements, Inc. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - The Nationalities Services Center. (Cleveland, Ohio), 1957 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - United Service for New Americans (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - The Welfare Federation of Cleveland (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - United Community Chest Councils of America (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - ASI Conferences, 25.
    - Conference - (Dr. Stewart Grant Cole), February 5, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Conference - (Dr. Henry B. Hazard and Mrs. Maurice Boie La Barre), October 16, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Conference, October 16, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Advisory Committee on Intercultural Education in the Country (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Alpenfels Meetings, March 10, 11, 12, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Americanization classes - Forbes School (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Christmas Sing (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Chinese Recreation Programs - ASI (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Committee on Clearance of Intercultural Education Activities, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Conferences, 26.
    - ASI Cooperation with Urban League. ASI National Conference, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Allegheny County Conference on Family Life (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Nairo Conference, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Nairo Conference, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - International Conference of Social Work (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
    - 2nd International Conference of Social Work (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 3rd International Conference of Social Work (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Study, Diagnosis, Treatment Sequence as an Aid to Initiating Community Organization Service, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Supervision (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Group Work Records (of Dr. Grace Coyle), 1936 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Community Organizations (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Group Work Process (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - National Conference of Social Welfare, Beginning 1957- (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - National Conference of Social Welfare and Reservations (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - National Conference of Social Work and Community Organization and Planning, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Research on Ethnic and Nationality Groups, II.
  Series II consists of ASI research on ethnic and nationality groups. The contents include a survey conducted by the ASI of local ethnic organizations and material relating to the history, customs and culture of the groups. The files are arranged alphabetically by name of cultural group some of which include: Bulgarians, Carpo-Russian, Croatian, Chinese, Czechoslovakian, Estonians, Germans, Greeks, Hungarians, Italians, Irish, Jewish, Japanese, Polish, Slovaks, Ukrainians and Yugoslavs, as well as others.
  - British Isles-Daughters of Scotia (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - British Isles-Order of Scottish Clans (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - British Isles-Ancient Order of Hibernians (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - British Isles-Knights of Equity, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - American Bulgarian League, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Bulgarian (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Bulgarian Church Society, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Bulgaro-Macedonian Benefit League, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Bulgarian- "Star" (Women's Bulgarian Organization), 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Canadian - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Carpatho-Russian- Choral, dance and instrumental Groups (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Carpatho-Russian- Customs and Festivals (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Carpatho-Russian- Greek Catholic Union of the U.S.A. (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Carpatho-Russian- Church-Carpatho-Russian (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Carpatho-Russian-Bibliography General (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Carpatho-Russian- United Russian Orthodox Brotherhood of America, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Carpatho-Russian- United Societies of Greek Catholic Religion, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Carpatho-Russian- Russian Orthodox Women's Mutual Aid Society, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Chinese People in Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Chinese-Customs - Festivals (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Croatian-Croatian Fraternal Union of America, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Croatian-Choral, dance and instrumental Groups - Croatian (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Croatian-Folk Dance groups (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Croatian-Organizations (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Croatian-St. Nickolas Church (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Croatian-Pen-Prints of Croatian History, Brief Historical Description of cities, territories and antiquities of Croatia (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Czechoslovak - Czech American National Alliance, Pittsburgh Branch, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Estonia-Bibliographies - misc - Estonia (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Estonia-Customs - Festivals (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Estonia-Misc - Estonia (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Ethiopia - Bibliographies (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Greek and German- Church - German (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - German Society (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Greek and German- St. Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Greek and German- American Hellenic Education Progressive Association, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Greek and German- American Hellenic Educational Progressive Association (Women), 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Greek and German- Catholic Knights of St. George Pub (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - German Organizations (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - F.L.G. - German (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Greek and German- History - German (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Greek and German- Greater Beneficial Union of Pittsburgh, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Greek Am. Progressive Assoc. (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Hungarian-American Social Association, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hungarian- ASI - Hungarians Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hungarian Churches and Societies Com., 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hungarian Reformed Federation of America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hungarian- Study of Girls in Pittsburgh-Hungarian - Ann Smith's Survey (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hungarian- United Magyar Civic Association of Pennsylvania, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hungarian- Verhovay Fraternal Insurance, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - India-C.O. Series on India, C. S. Monitor (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - India-Bibliographies (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - India-Customs Festivals (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Irish- Bibliographies (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Irish- Customs Festivals (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Irish- History (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Irish- Music and the Arts (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Italian-Choral, dance groups (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Italian-Federation Sons of Columbus of America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Italian-History (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Italian-Independent Sons of Italy, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Italian-Italian Sons and Daughters of America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Italian-Order of Sons of Italy in America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Japan - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Community in Pittsburgh (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Jewish-Anti-Semitism (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Jewish-Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Jewish-Customs and Festivals (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Jewish-Zionism (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Latin America-Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Latin America-History (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Latin America-Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Latvia - History (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Lebanon - Customs and Festivals (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Lithuanian-Eastern Church (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Lithuanian-Customs and Festivals (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Lithuanian-Lithuanian Alliance of America. (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Lithuanian Citizens Society of W. Penna., (Men), 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Lithuanian Citizens Society of W. Penna., (Women), 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Lithuanian Literary Association, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Lithuanian-Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Lithuanian-Sons of Lithuania, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Lithuanian-United Lithuanian Relief Fund of America (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Mexico - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Negro-Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Negro-Music and Arts (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Negro-Outstanding American Negroes Exhibit - Harmon Foundation, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Negro-Studies (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - New Zealand - Bibliographies (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Norway - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Polish- American Union Polish Brotherhood of St. Joseph, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Polish- Bibliographies (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Polish- Central Council of Polish Organizations (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Polish- Choral, Dance and groups (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Polish- Church (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Polish- Group Record - Rover Club (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Polish- History (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Polish- Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Polish- Organizations (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Polish American Congress, W. Pa. Divs, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Polish Arts League (local group only), 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Polish Falcons of America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Polish Roman Catholic Union of America (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Polish Women's Alliance of America (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Pennsylvania Dutch - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Puerto Rico - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Serbian- Choral, Dance groups (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Serbian- Serb National Federation (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Serbian- Catholic Slovak Brotherhood, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Slovak- Choral, dance and instrumental groups - Slovenian (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Slovak- Federation of Catholic Slovak Priests (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Slovak- First Catholic Slovak Ladies Union, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Slovak- First Catholic Slovak Union (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Slovak- Music and Arts (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Slovak- National Slovak Society of U.S.A., 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Slovak- Slovak Evangelical Union, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Slovak- Slovak Catholic Federation of America, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Slovak- Slovak League of America (Box 10, Folder 75-76)
  - Slovak- Zivena Beneficial Society, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Slovak- The Slovak National Council Abroad. Nationality (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Russian (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Scotch-Irish - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Scotland - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Serbian (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Scandinavian - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Siam - Festivals (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - South America - brazil (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - South America - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Slavs - General (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Slovenian - Customs and Festivals (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Spanish - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sweden - History (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Switzerland - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Syrian - Background (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Syrian - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Ukrainian - Choral, dance groups (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ukrainian - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Ukrainian Self Reliance (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Ukrainian Congress Committee (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ukrainian National Aid Association of America, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Welsh - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Yugoslavia - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Yugoslavia - National Geographic File (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Alphabetical Subject Files, III.
  Series III contains material that the ASI for general purposes and research for special projects and educational distribution. They are arranged as an alphabetical subject file with descriptive headings supplied by the ASI. Material in this section may overlap, duplicate, or fill in the gaps of other series reflecting the original ASI filing scheme. General topics include, but are not limited to, census and population statistics, civil rights, immigration, mental health, prejudice and discrimination, ethnic and nationality groups, religion, studies and surveys of Allegheny County, Pittsburgh, the Steel Valley and other local communities.
  - Aged, 1.
    - Aged (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Aliens, 2.
    - Alien Address Report (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Aliens, 1952-1958 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Alien - Children (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Aliens and Citizenship (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Alien - Citizenship education (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Alien Citizenship Procedures (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Alien Enemy Hearing Boards (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Alien Statistics (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Aliens - Employment of Aliens (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - General Assistance and the Alien in Pennsylvania (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Legislation - Pennsylvania Public Assistance for Aliens (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Aliens - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Alien registration - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - McCarran Act - Alien Legislation (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Orientation New Arrivals (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Pennsylvania - Aliens (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Art - Handcraft, 3.
    - Art - Handcraft - Projects and Suggestions of Foreign Handcraft Exhibits (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Bibliography, 4.
    - Bibliography - Refugees (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Bibliography - School of Applied Social Sciences (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Publishers Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Social Work Bibliography (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Camping, 5.
    - Interculture and Interracial camping (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - National Intercultural Committee American Camping Association, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 47-48)
    - Camps - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Children, 6.
    - Children of Other Lands - bibliography (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - White House Conference on Children Youth (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Youth - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Census, 7.
    - Census, 1910, 1920, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Census, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Census, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Census - Pittsburgh Adjacent Areas Allegheny County, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Census - employment, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Census - Industrial Classifications, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Census - Mother Tongue, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Census - Pennsylvania, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Census figures - ASI, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Census, Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - Problems of a Changing population (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Religious bodies, 1926-1936 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship, 8.
    - Citizenship - bibliography (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Citizenship, Loss of (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Manual for Naturalization (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Program Aids for Citizenship Recognition Ceremonies (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Citizenship. (misc., speeches, etc.) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Citizenship Studies (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Civil Rights, 9.
    - Civil Rights - Articles etc. Civil Liberties (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - American Red Cross, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 12a)
    - Council of Churches (Box 12, Folder 12b)
    - Committee on Foreign Students, Foreign Policy Association (Box 12, Folder 12c)
    - Nationality Rooms, University of Pittsburgh (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Penna. State Employment Service (Box 12, Folder 12e)
  - Community Studies - Out of town, 10.
    - Cleveland (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Department of Public Welfare (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - F.E.P.C., 11.
    - Federal Security Agency. Social Security Board (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - F.E.P.C. Institute (Urban League and F.E.P.C.), 1953 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - F.E.P.C. Institute, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Fraternal Organizations, 12.
    - Catholic Knights of St. George, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Degree of Honor Protective Association (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Maccabees Great Camp for Pennsylvania, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Protected Home Circle, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Royal Arcanum, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Supreme Forest Woodmen Circle, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Women's Benefit Association, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Workingmen's Beneficial Union of Pittsburgh (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Aid Association of Lutheran (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Fraternal Societies of Greater Pittsburgh (Box 12, Folder 26a-b)
  - Holidays, 13.
    - Holidays (also Jewish) (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Christmas - Christmas Customs (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Christmas Carols - Misc. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Christmas - Misc - Poland (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Housing, 14.
    - Housing, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Housing, 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Housing, 1953-1958 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Testimony prepared for Senate Subcommittee on Housing, December 13, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Housing and the Foreign Born (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Action Housing (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Housing - Restrictive Covenants (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Housing-Clippings (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Agencies on Housing (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Housing Authority of City of Pittsburgh (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Housing - Civic Unity Council (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Housing - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Immigration, 15.
    - Immigrant Arrivals in Pittsburgh District, public schools, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Immigration - miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Industry and Business, 16.
    - Industry and Business (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Integration, 17.
    - Integration - Assimilation and Accommodation (Box 12, Folder 46-48)
  - Intercultural Education, 18.
    - A Portfolio of Material for Youth Leaders, To Promote Better Human Relations Int. ed. (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Pittsburgh Public Schools - Intercultural Education Program (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Springfield Plan on Intercultural Education. (Box 12, Folder 51)